# KEVIN MERRICK OLIVIER

## MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER / DATA SCIENTIST

🗷 kevinmolivier@gmail.com 🔇 kmolivier.com 📞 (202) 657-6005 👂 York, England | Singer Island, Florida 🛚 in kevin-m-olivier 🗘 K-Merrick

## **SUMMARY**

As a passionate data scientist, I am eager to apply my skills in the field of machine learning engineering to solve complex problems and gain valuable insights from raw data. My educational background, which includes a PhD in epistemology, has trained me to evaluate every problem critically and often think outside of the box. I am also an experienced private investigator (6 years), leveraging my research and analytical skills in completing assignments for Fortune 500 companies.

## **PROJECTS**

#### Telecom Churn Prediction

Sept. 2021

Designed and implemented a custom stacking model, using gradient boosting base models, to predict customer churn with a goal of an AUC-ROC score of at least .88. Final score of stacked model was .963.

#### Sept 2021 Tabular Competition - Custom Stacking

Sept. 2021

Created a notebook to demonstrate to colleagues how model stacking and hyperparameter tuning using Bayesian optimization is performed. Notebook includes exploratory data analysis, feature engineering, hyperparameter optimization with Optuna, and custom functions to implement model stacking.

### Sept 2021 Tabular Competition - Blending Ensemble

Sept. 2021

Created a notebook to demonstrate to colleagues how model blending is performed. Notebook includes exploratory data analysis, missing value imputation, and custom functions to create and test blended model.

#### Computer Vision - Age Prediction

Aug. 2021

Created a custom ResNet50 deep learning model using Keras to predict the age of customers from images. Employed an image data generator to periodically load

#### Natural Language Processing - Sentiment Analysis

Aug. 2021

Trained and tested various models using NLTK, spaCy, TF-IDF, and BERT to determine whether IMDB movie reviews were positive or negative.

## Time Series Forecasting

July 2021

Conducted in-depth time-series analysis witht he goal of developing a regression model to predict hourly taxi orders. This involved stationarization using differencing, feature engineering, and developing/testing several regression models.

## Game Sales Analysis

June 2021

Carried out extensive data preprocessing and exploratory data analysis to uncover trends in worldwide game sales that may be used to create lucrative targeted advertisements.

## **Gold Production Optimization**

June 2021

Trained and evaluated several regression models to predict the amount of gold recovered via a complex extraction process from raw gold ore. This required extensive exploratory data analysis and data preprocessing, which included imputing nulls using the KNN method.

#### Publication: Agent Reliabilism and Inferential Knowledge from Iune Gettiered Belief 2020

Published (as single author in a top-rated philosophy journal) an in-depth research paper on acquiring inferential knowledge from non-knowledge. This possibility directly challenges the orthodox view that inferential knowledge can only be acquired from known premises.

## SKILLS

DATA SCIENCE: Python (Pandas, NumPy, NLTK, SciPy, imblearn, etc.), SQL, Machine Learning (SciKit-Learn, Keras, Tensorflow),

Hyperparameter Optimization (Optuna, Hyperopt).

Visualization (Matplotlib, Seaborn), Statistical Analysis, Data Mining, Spark, Git GENERAL: Excellent Communication Skills, Research & Analysis, Effective Teaching, Investigations, Scrum, Project Management

## **EDUCATION**

#### Practicum by Yandex

Jan. 2021 - Sept. 2021

Certification Data Science 2021

Intensive 9-month data science bootcamp, covering important topics relating to the fields of data science and machine learning, including topics such as model creation, speech recognition, image classification, developing neural networks, etc. Promoted to senior student, responsible for aiding other students. Completed 16 real-world projects.

#### University of Aberdeen

Oct. 2016 - Jan. 2021

PhD Epistemology 2021

Obtained a PhD in analytic philosopy, with a specialization in Epistemology. Passed the external examination with no corrections. Recipient of Elphinstone Scholarship.

## **University of Groningen**

July 2013 - July 2014

MA Philosophy 2014

Master of Arts in analytic philosophy, with a specialization in Epistemology.

## University of Florida

Feb. 2008 - Nov. 2012

Bachelor of Arts in analytic philosophy. Recipient of full scholarship.

## **EMPLOYMENT**

Practicum by Yandex, Senior Student, Remote

Apr. 2021 - Current

As a senior student, I aid the tutors and instructors in answering students' questions regarding programming, data science, and machine learning, and help them complete their projects.

### Prudential Associates,

Private Detective / Background Researcher, Rockville, MD Head of the background check department, responsible for interacting directly

Ian. 2015 -Current

with clients from large companies, including some Fortune 500. Currently working on introducing sentiment analysis using BERT to our social media threat detection system.

## University of Aberdeen, Teaching Assistant,

Apr. 2017 - Jan. 2018

Aberdeen, Scotland

Worked as a teaching assistant for courses on ethics and contraversial philosophical questions. Responsible for creating and delivering comprehensive weekly tutorials to numerous classes

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

Intro to Machine Learning, Kaggle

Accelerating Deep Learning with GPUs, IBM D	Developer Skills Network 2021
---	-------------------------------

Data Science / Machine Learning Professional, Practicum by Yandex 2021

Intermediate Machine Learning, Kaggle 2021

Tutor Academy Master Course, Practicum by Yandex 2021

Python, Kaggle 2021

Introduction to Git and Github, Coursera 2021

SQL for Data Science, Coursers 2020

Python for Everybody, Coursera 2020

Individual Certifications Include: Python Basics; Python Classes and Inheritance; Retriving, Processing, and Visualizing Data with Python; Python Data Structures; Using Databases with Python; Using Python to Access Web Data

#### Professional Scrum Master, Scrum.org

2020

2021